{
    "id": "76f2b45e5e7545a6bd1e399ff44d4fed",
    "title": "Kinds of Sentences | Grammar Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "c40e5212f8b74b38be9357dfd278241e",
            "title": "Kinds of Sentences | Grammar Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "Mother was busy cooking for the guests who were arriving in the evening.",
                    "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. Clauses introduced by relative pronouns like who, which, that, whom and whose are subordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The person who was injured in the accident needed help immediately.",
                    "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. Clauses introduced by relative pronouns like who, which, that, whom and whose are subordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Whatever you learn at school will help you in the future.",
                    "description": "Here the clause 'whatever you learn at school' is a subordinate noun clause. Sentences that contain subordinate clauses are complex sentences. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Alice cooked dinner and Mike tidied the rooms.",
                    "description": "A compound sentence consists of two or more coordinate clauses. Clauses connected by the conjunctions and, so, but, or, for, nor etc are coordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I had a headache but I enjoyed the movie.",
                    "description": "A compound sentence consists of two or more coordinate clauses. Clauses connected by but are coordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "In spite of having a headache I enjoyed the movie.",
                    "description": "The above sentence has just one clause and hence it is a simple sentence.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Although I had a headache, I enjoyed the movie.",
                    "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. Clauses introduced by the subordinating conjunctions though and although are subordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "We cancelled the picnic because of the rain.",
                    "description": "The above sentence has just one finite verb and hence it is a simple sentence. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "He is either a fool or a lunatic.",
                    "description": "Clauses connected by the coordinating conjunction 'either...or' are coordinate clauses and hence the above sentence is a compound sentence. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "I don't know whether he will arrive.",
                    "description": "The above sentence has one main clause and one subordinate noun clause and hence it is a complex sentence. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You should have asked me before using my computer.",
                    "description": "The above sentence has just one finite verb and hence one clause. So it is a simple sentence. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Compound sentence",
                        "Complex sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "The girl who won the first prize is my neighbor's daughter.",
                    "description": "A complex sentence has one main clause and one or more subordinate clauses. Clauses introduced by relative pronouns like who, which, that, whom and whose are subordinate clauses. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "Simple sentence",
                        "Complex sentence",
                        "Compound sentence"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}